使代码更可读的另一件事
Another thing that makes code more readable
很好的利用了空白，空格，缩进，
is good use of whitespace, spaces, indentations,
断线。
line breaks.
所以这个跳跃的例子不太擅长。
So this leap example is not so good at.
你会注意到这是一个其他人都不在的地方
You'll notice here is a place where the else is not
与它的if排成一行。
lined up with its if.
这是一个国际单项体育联合会不与其他人排队的地方
Here's a place where the if isn't lined up with the other
如果在同一个街区。
if that's in the same block.
没有充分的理由造成压痕不良，
No good reason for having bad indentation,
它使你的代码更难阅读。
it makes your code harder to read.
你的程序编辑器有一个自动功能
And your programming editor has an automatic feature
重新格式化代码。
that reformats code.
所以你应该用这个。
So you should just use that.
戴夫，你的例子在这方面做得更好。
Dave, your example does much better at this.
你注意到了，所有其他的如果都排得很好。
You notice, all of these else ifs are all nicely lined up.
但不仅如此，还利用了空间
But not only that, also uses spaces
把这些数字排成一行
to line up these numbers so that you
更容易检查。
can check them much more easily.
我们已经看到我们想要摆脱
We've already seen that we want to get rid
所有的重复。
of all of this repetition.
但是如果你这样做了你的代码必须有规律性，
But if you do you have to have regularity in your code,
如果使用缩进和间距
it's great if you use indentation and spacing to make
它非常清晰易读，易于检查。
it very clear and easy to read and easy to check.
在代码行中放置空格也很重要。
It's also important to put spaces within your code lines.
例如，这个表达式非常拥挤。
So for example, this expression is very crowded.
它只是一个没有空格的连续字符串。
It's just a string of continuous characters with no spaces.
把它想象成一句话，
Think about it rather like a sentence,
你想把空间放在好的地方
and you want to put spaces at good places
把句子中的单词分开
to separate the words of your sentence
为了让它更容易阅读。
in order to make it easier to read.
关于空白我想说的最后一件事
Final thing I want to say about whitespace
你应该避免在代码中使用制表符。
is that you should avoid having tab characters in your code.
你应该使用空格字符。
You should use space characters.
注意，当我说tab时，我真正的意思是
Notice that when I say tab, what I really mean
是制表符，不是按制表符时发生的情况
is the tab character, not what happens when you push the Tab
按键盘上的键。
key on your keyboard.
聪明的编辑会做聪明的事
A smart editor will do something smart
当你按Tab键时。
when you push the Tab key.
为什么我们不想要制表符呢？
So why don't we want tab characters?
原因是不同的工具
Well, the reason is that different tools treat
标签字符不同。
tab characters differently.
我们来看一个例子。
And lets look at an example.
这是我们在Eclipse中的leap代码。
So here's our leap code in Eclipse.
我们已经批评过这个凹痕了，
And we've already criticized this indentation a little,
但在很大程度上，一切都很好。
but for the most part, it's doing OK.
这个if和它的其他if排成一列。
This if is lined up with its else.
这群人的头上都是花括号。
This public is lined up with its end curly brace.
但现在如果我用另一个工具看这段代码，
But now if I look at this code in a different tool,
比如说，在网络浏览器中查看，
let's say, look at it in a web browser,
突然之间事情就大不一样了，对吧？
suddenly things are dramatically different, right?
这个字符串变量声明的目的远不止于此
This string variable declaration is intended way farther
当我在浏览器中查看时
when I'm looking at it in the browser than when
我在月食中看到它。
I'm looking at it in Eclipse.
这个if，你找不到对应于这个if的else。
This if, you can't find the else that corresponds to this if.
好像刚用两个大括号结束。
It looks like it's just ended with two curly braces.
那这里发生了什么？
So what happened here?
发生了什么事，我们都不知道，
Well, what happened is, unbeknownst to us,
在不可见的情况下，这段代码实际上是混合使用了制表符
invisibly, this code is actually using a mix of tab characters
对应于像这样的跳跃和空格字符
which correspond to jumps like this and space characters
它代表着单一的空间发展。
which represent just single space advances.
在Eclipse中，默认值是tab表示四个空格，
And in Eclipse, the default is that a tab means four spaces,
它跳过四个空格，而在许多其他工具中，
it jumps four spaces, whereas in many other tools,
包括web浏览器，还有很多文本编辑器，
including web browsers but also a lot of text editors,
这个跳跃实际上相当于8个空格。
that jump actually corresponds to eight spaces.
所以你最终会变得非常不一致和怪异
So you end up with very inconsistent and weird
缩进当你使用制表符和空格的混合时。
indentation when using you're using a mix of tab and spaces.
最好的做法是配置程序编辑器。
The best thing to do is to configure your program editor.
在Eclipse中，您可以在preferences中这样做
And in Eclipse, you can do this in preferences
所以，与其允许制表符和空格，
so that, instead of allowing tabs and spaces,
你只使用空格。
you're using spaces only.
然后，即使我按Tab键--让我来这里
Then, even if I press the Tab key-- so let me just go here
然后按Tab键——Eclipse将实际执行的操作
and press the Tab key-- what Eclipse will actually do
是插入空格而不是制表符。
is insert spaces instead of a tab character.
它会以一种聪明的方式做到这一点。
And it'll do that in a smart way.
如果我选择这里的所有内容，我可以修正缩进，
And if I select everything here, I can correct the indentation,
你会注意到它都变成了空间。
and you'll notice that it all turns into spaces.
现在，如果我在浏览器中查看它，
Now, if I view it in the browser,
这些空间被视为单个空间，
those spaces are treated as single spaces,
它会以同样的方式缩进。
and it's going to indent exactly the same way.
所以一定要设置程序编辑器插入
So always set your programming editor inserts
当然，除非，
to space characters unless, of course,
你所在的团队
the team you're working with has exactly
相反的政策，在这种情况下
the opposite policy, in which case
你应该做他们做的任何事。
you should do whatever they do.
但如果你自己做决定，
But if you're making the decision yourself,
我的建议是使用空间。
my advice is to use spaces.